Robert Smith Collection relating to Letterio Calapai
Robert Smith Collection relating to Letterio Calapai
1950-1995
Smith, Robert C.
0.25 linear ft.
Printed material and memorabilia relating to the Italian-American artist.
4596713
Biographical History
Letterio Calapai was an Italian-American painter, engraver, illustrator, printmaker who worked in New York City and Chicago.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Robert Smith Collection relating to Letterio Calapai consists of printed material and memorabilia relating to the Italian-American artist.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by type or topic.
Related Material
See also the
Letterio Calapai Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Art -- Illustrators; Calapai, Letterio, 1902-1993.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Engravers -- United States.; Etchers -- United States.; Illustrators -- United States.; Italian Americans.; Painters -- United States.; Printmakers -- United States.; Wood-engravers -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Photographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert C. Smith, 2015.
Inventory
- Artwork
  - Print, "The mischievous dog" by Calapai, 1980; original print in decorative folder, with accompanying letter from Calapai and a copy of "A Portfolio of Wood Engravings: Aesop's Fables," of which the print was part (Box 1)
  - Sketches of Smith, by Calapai, undated; photocopies (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming, from Calapai, 1968; 1980,; 1986,; 1991-1992,; undated (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Obituary, Deer Island (Maine) newspaper, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, candid photos of Calapai, Calapai and Smith, annotated by Smith (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Clippings and press releases, 1950; 1952,; 1981-1984,; 1986,; 1988,; 1991-1993,; 1995,; undated (Box 1)
  - Exhibit catalogs and invitations, 1961; 1967,; 1972,; 1977,; 1983,; 1986,; 1988,; 1991; some signed by artist; Rome exhibit catalog includes letter and enclosures from Calapai to Smith (Box 1)
  - Intaglio workshop, 1960-1961; course catalog from New School; postcard (Box 1)